[

  {"question":"Gavrilo Princip assasinated the Archduke Franz Ferdinand in 1914, leading to the onset of WWI. What country was he born in?",
    "choices":["Russia", "Germany", "Bosnia", "Serbia"], "correctAnswer":2},
  {"question":"What was Attila the Hun also known as?", 
    "choices":["The Scourge of the West", "The Scourge of God", 
              "The Scourge of the Papacy","Jody Highroller"], "correctAnswer":1},
  {"question":"In what year did the Great Fire of London occur?",
    "choices":["1666", "666", "1766", "1966"], "correctAnswer":0},
  {"question":"Which American politician led infamous anti-communist hearings in 1954?",
     "choices":["Joseph McCarthy", "John McCain","William McKinley", "Ronald McDonald" ],
              "correctAnswer":0},
  {"question":"The American invasion of Iraq in 1991 was known as Operation.. ?",
    "choices":["Desert Wind", "Desert flower", "Desert Cactus", "Desert Storm"], "correctAnswer":3},
  {"question":"What international confrontation during the cold war nearly led to nuclear weapons being used in open warfare?",
    "choices":["The Cuban Rum Crisis", "The Cuban Missile Crisis", "The Cuban Embargo Crisis",
             "The Cuban Salsa Crisis"], "correctAnswer":1},
  {"question":"Who was 'founder' and first Governor-General of Pakistan in 1947?",
    "choices":["M. Gandhi", "J. Nehru", "M. Jinnah", "L. Khan"], "correctAnswer":2},
  {"question":"Which great Spanish military leader famously faught for both the Spanish and the Moors during the Reconquista?",
    "choices":["El Empecinado","El Greco","El Cid","Elton John"], "correctAnswer":2},
  {"question":"What did Julius Caesar cross in 49 BC to begin the Great Roman Civil War?",
    "choices":["The Alps", "The Rubicon", "The English Channel",
             "His Shoelaces"], "correctAnswer":1},
  {"question":"What city did the Ottoman Sultan Mehmed II 'The conqueror' capture in 1453?",
    "choices":["Rome", "Vienna", "Jerusalem", "Constantinople"], "correctAnswer":3}

]